Dobromir Marinov

Cambridge, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662

mr.d.marinov@gmail.com

https://dmarinov.com/

Personal Profile

I am a software engineer with more than 3 years of professional experience. As part of my apprenticeship degree at the University of Essex, I achieved the highest degree mark in the computer science and electronic engineering department. My main research interest is in machine learning and I have successfully completed both a research-based, and an applied machine learning projects, as part of my education.

Employment

Swim.Ai

Software Developer

Cambridge, United Kingdom

September 2019 - Present

- Developing a distributed software platform for edge computing and real-time applications.
- Building commercial products based on the core system.
- Java, Pyhton, JavaScript, TypeScript.

MSX International

Software Developer (Machine Learning)

- Development of machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building and deployment of microservices using cloud platforms.
- Python, R, AWS, Docker, Redshift, LATEX.

MSX International

Software Developer

- Developing web applications for the automotive industry.
- Java, Oracle, Freemarker, Liferay, Hibernate, Gradle, Selenium.

Colchester, United Kingdom

Colchester, United Kingdom June 2018 – September 2019

November 2016 - June 2018

StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites for business clients.
- PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Laravel, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria July 2016 – September 2016

1

Education

University of Essex

BSc Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer)

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2016 – September 2019

Grade:

First-class honours degree with an award for highest degree mark in the computer science and electronic engineering department.

University-based Capstone Project:

Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

Work-based Capstone Project:

Creating a machine learning system for prioritisation of customer calls in a call centre.

Relevant Modules:

- Software engineering.
- Data structures and algorithms.
- Evolutionary computation and genetic programming.
- Advanced programming.

Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

• Learning under different training and testing distributions.

- \bullet Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the modelling and analysis of complex systems.
- Artificial intelligence and neural networks in analytics.

High School of Mathematics

Secondary education

- Program with extensive study of mathematics, english and IT.
- Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria September 2011 – June 2016

Awards

Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Prize

University of Essex

 Awarded to the final year student who achieves the highest degree mark. Colchester, United Kingdom July 2019

mark.

The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the second-year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2018

K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

Colchester, United Kingdom

University of Essex

September 2017

• Awarded to the top 4 first-year students, in CSEE, with the best overall mark.

Award of Excellence

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

High School of Mathematics

June 2016

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

Certificates

Tech Industry Gold Certificate of Recognition

London, United Kingdom

June 2019

Tech Partnership Degrees

• Nominated by the University of Essex for outstanding academic achievements and awarded by the Tech Partnership Degrees.

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2019

• Certificate for completing a mandatory course in GDPR.

Information Security

Colchester, United Kingdom

MSX International

MSX International

 $April\ 2019$

Certificate for completing a mandatory course in information security.

StangaOne1 Academy

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

StangaOne1

January 2016 - May 2016

- Certificate for successfully completing a web development course.
- PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML 5, CSS 3.

Publications

Published Papers

D. Marinov and D. Karapetyan, "Hyperparameter Optimisation with Early Termination of Poor Performers," Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Conference 2019, September 2019.

Working Papers

D. Marinov and D. Karapetyan, "Early prediction of model accuracy for hyperparameter optimisation of convolutional neural networks," to be submitted in Journal of Heuristics, by the end of December 2019.